<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>German Language on Neetz World</title>
    <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/tags/german-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in German Language on Neetz World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neetabirajdar.github.io/tags/german-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alphabets in German</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_alphabets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_alphabets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;Alphabet&lt;/em&gt; is the building block of language. The German Language is no different, it is just the pronunciation of alphabets and a few new alphabets are more than English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I will include the alphabet, the pronunciation of each, and examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greeting and Sendoff</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning something should be done in steps especially if that is Language learning. &lt;em&gt;Greeting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sendoff&lt;/em&gt; are the best way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with this and feel a lot more comfortable when I am in Restaurants or Grocery shops saying these basic phrases. I see smiles on their faces when I start with a greeting in German and if I cannot frame a sentence after it, they try to understand my half-German and half-English. Haha .. off course appreciate my efforts.😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this happens to a lot of us(if you are not German off course). So, let us start with the type of phases we have for this in German and see their examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talking to people is not that easy especially when you want to do that in a language you are just learning 🤓. There are some basic questions that people want to know when you are meeting them for the first time. So, let&amp;rsquo;s ask some basic questions and answer them in German. Also, understand the meaning of them in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways in German to speak to people, the formal way which applies to the places like Offices, restaurants, etc and there is the informal way which can be used with Friends and Family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we will see the questions which people normally ask while the introduction and answer them formally and informally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbs</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_verbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verbs&lt;/strong&gt; are really important if you want to learn and understand any language. In this blog, I have added some basic examples of how Regular and Irregular verbs look like with different forms of Nouns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German is a complicated language (of course my personal opinion 😉) as there are a lot of exceptions. When you are comfortable with one rule, there comes a new one which does not like to follow rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha ha! Fun aside, let&amp;rsquo;s learn some of the basic verbs and conjugate them with different nouns. Also, see the use of those verbs within a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
