<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neeta&#39;s World on Neetz World</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neeta&#39;s World on Neetz World</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_machine_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_machine_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have heard about Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics a lot. Everyone is talking about these topics. Machine learning seemed very interesting topic to get into, I know I am late already but &amp;ldquo;Better late than never 😁&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am starting on these topic, so I thought it would be amazing to share with you, my learnings and hope that will help you too.&#xA;So, Let start with what comes inside what.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sales Learnings for Startup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/startup_sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/startup_sales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-sales-the-lifeline-of-startups&#34;&gt;🚀 Sales: The Lifeline of Startups&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sales&lt;/strong&gt; is not just important—it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;mission-critical&lt;/strong&gt; for the success of an early-stage startup. While there are many pillars that hold up a startup, Sales is the engine that drives growth and survival. There&amp;rsquo;s a saying for startups: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do things that don’t scale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; And guess what? Sales is at the heart of this philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming from a tech background, diving into the &lt;em&gt;world of sales&lt;/em&gt; was like stepping into an entirely new dimension. It’s fascinating to learn &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;how sales works—how relationships are built, trust is earned, and deals are closed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. For me, it was more than just a challenge; it was a journey of discovery.🚀&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lean Startup Way</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/startup_lean_canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/startup_lean_canvas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-learnings-from-lean-startup-bootcamp&#34;&gt;My learnings from Lean Startup Bootcamp:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I heard about the &lt;code&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/code&gt; concept a few times since I have been on this new journey of entrepreneurship. Today was the day when I had my first session as the part of this journey which was on Lean Startup. It was interesting to see how the things are when you just read them and actually implement them on your idea with team.&#xA;It was an interesting session where I learned about &lt;em&gt;Lean Startup Methods and Principles, Why most Startups fails?, What to focus on initially when starting with a startup idea? and Lean Canvas&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colors in German</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_colors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Colors are beautiful.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Farbe&lt;/code&gt; is german word for &lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt;. When you wanna learn them in German Language, it sometimes get confusing to understand. So, I tried to make the learning as simple as possible with my cute little drawing 😁.&#xA;I have added a lot of examples for each and added information about different shades and rules for using them with objects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;colors&#34;&gt;Colors:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how all the basic colors are called in German with examples which I have drawn 👩🏻‍🎨.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alphabets in German</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_alphabets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_alphabets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;Alphabet&lt;/em&gt; is the building block of language. The German Language is no different, it is just the pronunciation of alphabets and a few new alphabets are more than English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I will include the alphabet, the pronunciation of each, and examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test Report With Pytest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_pytest_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_pytest_report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-test-report&#34;&gt;What is Test Report?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Test reporting is always important part of testing. It provides an overview of which testcases are working, which ones are failing and details like what happened if logged or printed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;calculator-example&#34;&gt;Calculator Example:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the following example for test reporting:&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Calculator App&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/neetaBirajdar/test_reporting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://github.com/neetaBirajdar/test_reporting&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-report-with-pytest&#34;&gt;Test Report with Pytest&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pytest&lt;/code&gt; is a very well known testing framework used in python test world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are multiple options for reporting that can be used along with Pytest to make the results easy to read and understand.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;pytest-html-report&#34;&gt;pytest-html Report:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/pytest-html/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://pypi.org/project/pytest-html/&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker with basic examples</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/docker_basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/docker_basic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-docker-&#34;&gt;What is Docker ?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a &lt;em&gt;open platform&lt;/em&gt; to deliver your application &lt;em&gt;faster&lt;/em&gt; to production.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It helps in developing, running, testing, shipping the &lt;em&gt;same environment&lt;/em&gt; without worrying about the host infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advantages:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suitable for progressive deployment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dynamic workload management and scaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cost efficient as compared to VMs(Virtual Machines)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open platform to use and to contribute&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Environment isolation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Easy to share&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;components-of-docker&#34;&gt;Components of Docker&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;docker components&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/docker_basic/components.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;docker-daemon&#34;&gt;Docker Daemon:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Listens to all the Docker API requests coming in the form of commands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manages Docker objects like &lt;em&gt;images&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;containers&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;networks&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;volumnes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It also communicate with other docker-daemons to manage the docker-service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;docker-client&#34;&gt;Docker Client:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is the primary way with which user can interact with docker-daemon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Listens to the commands like &lt;code&gt;docker run&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;docker build&lt;/code&gt; (via Docker APIs) and sends it to docker-daemon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This client can communicate to multiple docker-daemons at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;docker-registry&#34;&gt;Docker Registry:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The place to store the docker images is called docker registry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/strong&gt; is the public registry available for everyone to access.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can &lt;code&gt;docker pull&lt;/code&gt; the docker-image and &lt;code&gt;docker push&lt;/code&gt; your docker-image to the registry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;docker-objects&#34;&gt;Docker Objects:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a &lt;em&gt;read-only template&lt;/em&gt; which defines the environment you want to set for your application.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Created with the file called &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; (name should be the same).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Each instruction in Dockerfile is a &lt;em&gt;layer&lt;/em&gt;. Other images can also be used as layers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When you update and rebuild an image, only the layer which changed gets rebuilt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;containers&#34;&gt;Containers:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These are the &lt;em&gt;runnable instance&lt;/em&gt; of docker-images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Controlled via commands like &lt;code&gt;start&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;stop&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;create&lt;/code&gt; etc using docker-APIs or CLI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Containers can connect to one or more &lt;em&gt;networks&lt;/em&gt; and can attach &lt;em&gt;storage&lt;/em&gt; in the form of volumnes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All the containers are isolated from each other and its host machine too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-ways-to-create-a-container&#34;&gt;Two ways to create a container:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;Install the docker : &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; before you go further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MQTT with example</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tech_mqtt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-mqtt-&#34;&gt;What is MQTT ?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MQTT&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message Queue Telemetry Transport&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a &lt;em&gt;standard messaging protocal&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;IoT(Internet of Things)&lt;/em&gt; sector.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This was especially built for Machine-To-Machine(&lt;em&gt;M2M&lt;/em&gt;) communication.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a simple, lightwieght but effective way to transport messages across a lot of devices with minimal bandwidth using &lt;em&gt;publisher/subscriber&lt;/em&gt; model.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;components-of-mqtt&#34;&gt;Components of MQTT:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;MQTT Architecture&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/mqtt_arch.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MQTT Broker/Server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&#xA;It is server which routes published data to the subscriber who subscribed to that topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greeting and Sendoff</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning something should be done in steps especially if that is Language learning. &lt;em&gt;Greeting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sendoff&lt;/em&gt; are the best way to start.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started with this and feel a lot more comfortable when I am in Restaurants or Grocery shops saying these basic phrases. I see smiles on their faces when I start with a greeting in German and if I cannot frame a sentence after it, they try to understand my half-German and half-English. Haha .. off course appreciate my efforts.😄&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But I think this happens to a lot of us(if you are not German off course). So, let us start with the type of phases we have for this in German and see their examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talking to people is not that easy especially when you want to do that in a language you are just learning 🤓. There are some basic questions that people want to know when you are meeting them for the first time. So, let&amp;rsquo;s ask some basic questions and answer them in German. Also, understand the meaning of them in English.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two ways in German to speak to people, the formal way which applies to the places like Offices, restaurants, etc and there is the informal way which can be used with Friends and Family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we will see the questions which people normally ask while the introduction and answer them formally and informally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verbs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/german_verbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verbs&lt;/strong&gt; are really important if you want to learn and understand any language. In this blog, I have added some basic examples of how Regular and Irregular verbs look like with different forms of Nouns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;German is a complicated language (of course my personal opinion 😉) as there are a lot of exceptions. When you are comfortable with one rule, there comes a new one which does not like to follow rules.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ha ha! Fun aside, let&amp;rsquo;s learn some of the basic verbs and conjugate them with different nouns. Also, see the use of those verbs within a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;strong&gt;Neet&lt;/strong&gt;. I love having fun and learning new things. I am professionally a &lt;em&gt;Quality Assurance Automation Engineer&lt;/em&gt; who is super passionate about the Testing World and has fun &lt;em&gt;breaking&lt;/em&gt; applications. 😈&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My colleagues describe me as a well-organized and detail-oriented person professionally. My friends say that I am fun to be around. 😀&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe that life is limited, so &lt;code&gt;Try New Things&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Do What You Like The Most!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
