<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Neetz World</title>
    <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Neetz World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alphabets in German</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_alphabets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_alphabets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning &lt;em&gt;Alphabet&lt;/em&gt; is the building block of language. The German Language is no different, it is just the pronunciation of alphabets and a few new alphabets are more than English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I will include the alphabet, the pronunciation of each, and examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Report With Pytest</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/tech_pytest_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/tech_pytest_report/</guid>
      <description>What is Test Report? Test reporting is always important part of testing. It provides an overview of which testcases are working, which ones are failing and details like what happened if logged or printed.
Calculator Example: Use the following example for test reporting: Calculator App: https://github.com/neetaBirajdar/test_reporting Test Report with Pytest pytest is a very well known testing framework used in python test world. There are multiple options for reporting that can be used along with Pytest to make the results easy to read and understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker with basic examples</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/docker_basic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/docker_basic/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker ? Docker :
It is a open platform to deliver your application faster to production. It helps in developing, running, testing, shipping the same environment without worrying about the host infrastructure. Advantages: Suitable for progressive deployment Dynamic workload management and scaling Cost efficient as compared to VMs(Virtual Machines) Open platform to use and to contribute Environment isolation Easy to share Components of Docker Docker Daemon: Listens to all the Docker API requests coming in the form of commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT with example</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/tech_mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/tech_mqtt/</guid>
      <description>What is MQTT ? MQTT : Message Queue Telemetry Transport
It is a standard messaging protocal for IoT(Internet of Things) sector. This was especially built for Machine-To-Machine(M2M) communication. It is a simple, lightwieght but effective way to transport messages across a lot of devices with minimal bandwidth using publisher/subscriber model. Components of MQTT: MQTT Broker/Server: It is server which routes published data to the subscriber who subscribed to that topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greeting and Sendoff</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_greetings_sendoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning something should be done in steps especially if that is Language learning. &lt;em&gt;Greeting&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Sendoff&lt;/em&gt; are the best way to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with this and feel a lot more comfortable when I am in Restaurants or Grocery shops saying these basic phrases. I see smiles on their faces when I start with a greeting in German and if I cannot frame a sentence after it, they try to understand my half-German and half-English. Haha .. off course appreciate my efforts.😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think this happens to a lot of us(if you are not German off course). So, let us start with the type of phases we have for this in German and see their examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talking to people is not that easy especially when you want to do that in a language you are just learning 🤓. There are some basic questions that people want to know when you are meeting them for the first time. So, let&amp;rsquo;s ask some basic questions and answer them in German. Also, understand the meaning of them in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways in German to speak to people, the formal way which applies to the places like Offices, restaurants, etc and there is the informal way which can be used with Friends and Family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we will see the questions which people normally ask while the introduction and answer them formally and informally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbs</title>
      <link>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neetabirajdar.github.io/blog/german_verbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verbs&lt;/strong&gt; are really important if you want to learn and understand any language. In this blog, I have added some basic examples of how Regular and Irregular verbs look like with different forms of Nouns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German is a complicated language (of course my personal opinion 😉) as there are a lot of exceptions. When you are comfortable with one rule, there comes a new one which does not like to follow rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha ha! Fun aside, let&amp;rsquo;s learn some of the basic verbs and conjugate them with different nouns. Also, see the use of those verbs within a sentence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
